彼得：最近我最喜欢的机器人电影之一被称为“机器人和弗兰克”。
Peter: One of my favorite robot movies in recent times is called "Robot and Frank".
这是关于一个正处于早期阶段的老人之间的关系
And it's about the relationship between an elderly man who is suffering the early stages
老年痴呆症-他曾经是一个猫咪窃贼-以及照顾他的机器人。还有弗兰克
of dementia - he used to be a cat burglar - and the robot who looks after him. And Frank
是一个相当吝啬的角色，他的儿子发现它非常耗费精力和疲惫
is a fairly curmudgeonly character, and his son finds it pretty draining and exhausting
去拜访他并被虐待。所以他给他的父亲买了一个机器人，因为机器人会的
to go and visit him and be abused. So he buys his father a robot, because the robot will
照顾他。这对儿子亨特来说有点麻烦，而且他有效
look after him. And it's kind of a less bother for the son, Hunter, and he has effectively
将他父亲的照顾委托给一台机器，因为实际上他不那么痛苦
delegated the care of his father to a machine because it's less painful for him to actually
拜访他，父亲，他自己。
visit him, the father, himself.
所以你或许可以争辩说，这位父亲弗兰克会更好地照顾
So you could perhaps argue that this father, Frank, is going to be better looked after
与机器人。你想知道亨特是否通过购买他的方式在这里做正确的事
with the robot. Do you wonder whether Hunter is doing the right thing here by buying his
父亲一个机器人走开了？
father a robot and walking away?
道格：如果我们看看道义论，那么道义论就是“deon”，责任。道义论的关键
Doug: If we look at deontology, deontology is ‘deon’, duty. And key to deontology
是我满足那些我先前提出的标准所需的职责。自治，
are the sets of duties that are required to meet those criteria I laid out earlier. Autonomy,
非男性，对吗？所以在这种情况下，我们谈的是自治权和权利
non-maleficence, right? So in this case we're talking about autonomy and the right of the
个人过着充实而深思熟虑的生活。所以在这种情况下父亲正在被关注
individual to live a full and considered life. So the father in this case is being looked
在一台机器之后，儿子正在废除他对父亲的责任。有人可以说
after by a machine, the son is abrogating his duty to his father. And so one could say
这是不道德的。其次，到了什么程度呢？我认为有一台机器可以看
that that's unethical. Secondly, to what degree though? I think that having a machine to look
在某人之后，只要它符合父亲的自治标准，就可以了。
after somebody, as long as it fulfills the autonomy criterion for the father, it's fine.
只要他是自主的并且可以在机器人之外做出决定-不是问题。该
As long as he is autonomous and can make decisions outside of the robot - not a problem. The
机器人正在满足他的需求并且正在增加他的自主权。但那时，和
robot is serving his needs and is increasing his autonomy. But at that point where, and
这是一个照顾个人的家长式举动，对吧？但在这一点上
this is really a paternalistic move to look after an individual, right? But at the point
个人自治受到影响，换句话说他们无法做出决定，
that the individuals autonomy is impacted, in other words they can't make decisions,
或者他们做出的决定受到机器的影响，那么我认为这是不道德的。
or what decisions they made are affected by the machine, then I'd argue it's unethical.
而且我还认为儿子正在废除照顾的责任。
And I'd also argue that the duty of care is being abrogated by the son.
彼得：即使机器比儿子自己做得更好吗？
Peter: Even if the machine would do a better job of care than the son would himself?
道格：但这并没有废除个人的责任。
Doug: But this does not abrogate the individual for the duty.
彼得：好的。
Peter: Okay.
道格：你和我在一起？
Doug: You're with me?
彼得：是的。
Peter: Yup.
道格：但是没错，我同意你的观点。但是对父母的照顾责任是道德的，
Doug: But correct, I agree with you on that. But the duty of care to a parent is an ethical,
随着父母年龄的增长，我们都必须面对这种基本的道德窘境。
it's a fundamental ethical sort of quandary we all have to face as our parents get older.
彼得：当然。
Peter: Absolutely.
道格：但道德和道义论会认为你有这个职责而你实现了它。
Doug: But ethics and deontology would argue that you have this duty and you fulfill it.
彼得：那么......让我们走下一代而不是一代人。我们
Peter: So what about the... let's go down a generation instead of up a generation. We
在这个国家有很多关于学前教育，儿童保育和儿童保育费用的讨论
have a lot of discussion in this country about the cost of preschool care, childcare, and
我们无法让足够多的人去做那项工作。那么道德规范对于拥有什么呢？
that we can't get enough people to do that work. So what does ethics say about having
机器，机器人照顾幼儿园年龄的儿童或更年轻？他们吃饱了。
machines, robots looking after kindergarten age children or younger? They're well fed.
他们受到照顾。他们的尿布和尿布都改变了。也许他们玩的，
They're looked after. Their nappies and diapers are changed. Maybe they’re played with,
非常热情，也许比人类更多。
very enthusiastically, perhaps more than by a human.
道格：是的，我和你在一起。但我认为，我们再次使用相同的论点
Doug: Yeah, I'm with you. But I think that, again we use the same argument in terms of
责任，这是父母的责任。孝顺的责任，以及这需要什么。再说一次，
duty, and that's the duty of the parent. The filial duty, and what that entails. So again,
如果一个机器人补充那个孝顺的职责，那就好了。但如果它取代它-不好。所以它变成了
if a robot supplements that filial duty, good. But if it replaces it - not good. So it becomes
你必须谈判的灰色区域，因为如果一天结束的机器人使我们的
a grey area that you have to negotiate, because if a robot at the end of the day makes our
孩子更安全-我很喜欢那个。你知道，如果它不让他们进入
children safer – well I'm for that. You know, if it doesn't let them get onto the
街道和那种事情，我认为这很棒。但机器人无法取代责任
street and that sort of thing, I'd argue that's great. But a robot can't replace the duty
照顾父母。它做不到。至少不是现在。但仍然存在根本原因
of care of the parent. It can't do it. At least not now. But there's still that fundamental
个人对孩子的责任。
duty the individual has to their children.
彼得：还有他们的父母。
Peter: And to their parents.
道格：还有他们的父母，是的。你无法摆脱这种情况。
Doug: And to their parents, yeah. And you can't escape that.
彼得：所以写下来的地方，你的孩子和你父母的责任在哪里？
Peter: So where is that written down, the duty to your children and your parents?
道格：哦，它就在附近。
Doug: Oh, it's around.